From gentle to mental.
Me, Myself & Irene is a comedy film directed by Peter Farrelly.
Rhode Island State Trooper Charlie Baileygates has
a multiple personality disorder.
One personality is crazy and aggressive, while the
other is more friendly and laid back.
Both of these personalities fall in love with the same woman
named Irene after Charlie loses his medication.
Off. Charlie Baileygates / Hank Evans, played by Jim Carrey.
Irene P. Waters, played by Renée Zellweger.
Jamaal Baileygates, played by Anthony Anderson.
Colonel Partington, played by Robert Forster.
Agent Boshane, played by Richard Jenkins.
Agent Peterson, played by Zen Gesner.
Me, Myself & Irene is a 2000 American slapstick black comedy film produced, co-written, and
directed by the Farrelly brothers, and starring Jim Carrey and Renée Zellweger.
The film is about a Rhode Island state trooper named Charlie (Carrey) who, after years of continuously suppressing his feelings, suffers a psychotic breakdown that results in a second
personality, Hank, and must deal with his newfound condition while escorting a woman named Irene (Zellweger) who is being hunted by her mob-affiliated ex-boyfriend.
Chris Cooper, Robert Forster, and Richard Jenkins also star.
This was Carrey's first role in a 20th Century Fox film, along with being the
Farrelly brothers' second film with Carrey since Dumb and Dumber (1994).
Filming was done from May 11 to July 29, 1999, in various
locations in Rhode Island and Vermont.
Me, Myself & Irene was released on June 23, 2000, and was a box office success.
It received mixed reviews from film critics.
The film explores themes of schizophrenia, road trip, ex-cop,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.